<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></description>
<link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:55:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Four]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
HEAR THE PRAYER I bring before you, O Lord, that the soul of your servant Dean, which you have called to depart this life, may find a place in the eternal dwelling places of peace and light and be welcomed into the fellowship of your saints; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayernine.html">prayerNine</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-days.html">Days</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-of.html">of</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">Prayer</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-for.html">for</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-one.html">One</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-deceased.html">Deceased</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag--.html">-</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-day.html">Day</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-three.html">Three</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayerNine]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Days]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[of]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[for]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[One]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Deceased]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[-]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Day]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Three]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-06-day-four.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-06-day-four.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Sunday Called Septuagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Sunday Called Septuagesima, or the Third Sunday before Lent
</p>

<p>
O Lord, we beseech thee favourably to hear the prayers of thy people; that we, who are justly punished for our offences, may be mercifully delivered by thy goodness, for the glory of thy Name; through Jesus Christ our Saviour, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Ghost ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season changes to pre-Lent, the liturgical color is now Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-the-sunday-called-septuagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-the-sunday-called-septuagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Three]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased - Day Three
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
O GOD, YOUR MERCIES are more than we can know; hear my prayer for Dean and welcome him into the land of light and joy, in the fellowship of all your saints; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-day-three.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-day-three.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Two]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased - Day Two
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
TO YOU, O LORD, I commend the soul of your servant Dean, that being dead to the world, he may live to you; and whatever sins he has committed, through the frailty of our mortal nature, graciously wash away by the pardon of your most merciful loving kindness; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-04-day-two.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-04-day-two.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 18:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day One]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased - Day One
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
O GOD, YOU ARE FULL OF MERCY and ready to forgive; receive our prayers for the soul of your servant Dean, whom you have now called to depart out of this world: deliver him out of the hand of the enemy, hold him in everlasting remembrance, and command your holy angels to receive him and bring him into paradise: that as his hope and faith were in you, he may without fear or suffering enter the joys of eternal life; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-03-day-one.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-03-day-one.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 18:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fourth Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O God, who knowest us to be set in the midst of so many and great dangers, that by reason of the frailty of our nature we cannot always stand upright; Grant to us such strength and protection, as may support us in all dangers, and carry us through all temptations; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-29-the-fourth-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-29-the-fourth-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 10:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Third Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Third Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
Almighty and everlasting God, mercifully look upon our infirmities, and in all our dangers and necessities stretch forth thy right hand to help and defend us; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-22-the-third-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-22-the-third-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 10:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Second Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Second Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
Almighty and everlasting God, who dost govern all things in heaven and earth; Mercifully hear the supplications of thy people, and grant us thy peace all the days of our life; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-15-the-second-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-15-the-second-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The First Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
O Lord, we beseech thee mercifully to receive the prayers of thy people who call upon thee; and grant that they may both perceive and know what things they ought to do, and also may have grace and power faithfully to fulfil the same; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-litany.html">litany</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[litany]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-08-the-first-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-08-the-first-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Collect for The Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Collect for The Epiphany, or the Manifestation of Christ to the Gentiles
</p>

<p>
O God, who by the leading of a star didst manifest thy only-begotten Son to the Gentiles; Mercifully grant that we, who know thee now by faith, may after this life have the fruition of thy glorious Godhead; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-06-the-collect-for-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-06-the-collect-for-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 10:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[I'm Back!]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Yes, I’m back - yes, I know it’s been close to a year. There is a reason—actually several reasons over and above my tendancy to put things off. There will be some explanation and some catch-up, but not today. Not that long ago I reinstalled my accustomed OS, rebuilt emacs and rewrote my init.el, and am today getting some gitting caught up. So, the test I’m referring to is whether org-static-blog is dtrt, whether I can push to gist. Typing is hard with fingers crossed, so that’s it for now.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-testing.html">testing</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[testing]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-12-12-i'm-back!.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-12-12-i'm-back!.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 14:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Does it Matter?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Having asked “What is Truth?” and explored the flip side, falsehood, an obvious follow-on question becomes “Does it Matter?” Whether it’s a matter of our own thoughts or what others present to us, does truth or falsehood matter?
</p>

<p>
Should I be concerned whether I’m being told the truth, or whether I’m being lied to? Whether my own thought processes are in line with “consensus reality” or I’m seriously deluded? Does truth matter?
</p>

<p>
Certainly, sometimes it does, but then again, sometimes it doesn’t.
</p>

<p>
If I ask “Is this mushroom safe to eat?” as I’m about to pop it into my mouth, and my friend says, “Sure, perfectly safe” whether that’s true or false could be a matter of life or death. On the other hand, if I say Liv Tyler played Galadriel in the Lord of the Rings movies, and my friend agrees, we’d both be wrong, but it’s not likely to matter much at all — unless I’m about to bet my life savings on the answer.
</p>

<p>
So, whether telling the truth is important is entirely context-dependent. It depends on the consequences. Or is it? Is there some value to truth, or loss to error, that’s more subtle than these examples would suggest?
</p>

<p>
That’s a good question and one that’s going to take some more examination. We’ll come back to that one.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-02-06-does-it-matter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-02-06-does-it-matter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 12:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[What is Falsehood?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“All generalizations are false, including this one.”—Mark Twain
</p>

<p>
If Truth is “in conformity to fact or reality”, there must be something <i>not</i> in conformity to fact or reality. And of course there is:
</p>

<p>
Falsehood \False&ldquo;hood\, n. [False + -hood]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li>Want of truth or accuracy; an untrue assertion or
representation; error; misrepresentation; falsity.</li>
<li>A deliberate intentional assertion of what is known to be
untrue; a departure from moral integrity; a lie.</li>
<li>Treachery; deceit; perfidy; unfaithfulness.</li>
<li>A counterfeit; a false appearance; an imposture.</li>
</ol>
<p>
Syn: Falsity; lie; untruth; fiction; fabrication.
</p>

<p>
And, like truth, there’s a lot of weeds to get into regarding falsehood. Oh, it doesn’t always have to be complicated. In software development, for instance, we use Boolean or bivalent logic to determine whether a value is, say, equal to or greater than 100. If it is, the answer is “true” (or 1 in computer speak) and if it isn’t, it’s “false” (or 0). Very straightforward and clean.
</p>

<p>
Once we introduce a human into the mix, though, it gets complicated very quickly. Ask a person an equally straightforward question — say, “Do you have twenty dollars with you?” and the reply is “No”. If the answer, whether it’s “yes” or “no” is true, accurate, “in conformity to fact or reality” we’ve arrived at end of story.
</p>

<p>
However, if the answer is not true, not “in conformity to fact or reality” things get a bit more complicated. If we got an inaccurate reply in the computer example, that’s an error and our code is faulty or there’s a hardware issue. However, if our friend did have twenty dollars and said “no”, or didn’t and said “yes”, then there are several possibilities.
</p>

<p>
A simple mistake is one — definition 1. above. She left home with $35 and bought a $15 book before we met up. That leaves $20 in her mind, but she forgot sales tax and that $20 is actually $18.45. Or, she may believe that we’ll think less of her if she’s not carrying at least $20 dollars, so she says that she does when she knows that she doesn’t. In other words, we’ve been lied to — definition 2.
</p>

<p>
More complicated than simple Boolean logic, but still fairly straightforward. Of course, because we’ve introduced humans into the picture, there are additional complications. For example, there’s the classic “Does this dress make my butt look big” or “Am I too old to be playing rock ‘n’ roll?” Of course, if you’re being asked either the answer may well be “Yes”, and a “No” answer would be a lie, but a complicated lie. The complication will have to do at least in part with motivation — a lie to avoid hurting someone’s feelings with no other consequences isn’t quite the same as an identical lie to harm the other person. Lies are complicated enough to deserve further exploration.
</p>

<p>
“Want of truth” and “an untrue assertion” in the definition eventually sends us back to the definition of “true”, which includes much more than “in conformity to fact or reality.” It also includes “conformity to rule”, “that which is true or certain concerning any matter or subject”, and “righteousness; true religion”.
</p>

<p>
These aspects of “truth” bring in context — truth in “conformity to rule” depends on which rule. Dribbling the ball is required in basketball, an error in American football.
</p>

<p>
“That which is true or certain concerning any matter or subject” depends on the subject. A true statement about gravity when the subject is Newtonian physics is false if the subject is switched to Einsteinian physics.
</p>

<p>
And, of course, “Righteousness; true religion” depends not only upon which religion, but which sect within a given religion.
</p>

<p>
So, it looks like, before we can get down and dirty with saying things that conform with reality, we may need to explore not-truth a bit more.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-30-what-is-falsehood.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-30-what-is-falsehood.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 13:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[What is Truth?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“What is Truth?”—Pontius Pilate, Roman Prefect/Procurator of Palestine, 26-36 Anno Domini, quoted in John 18:38.
</p>

<p>
Pilate gets a bad rap for asking, but in truth, “truth” is complicated. My primary dictionaries, the 1913 <i>Webster’s Revised Unabridged</i> of 1913 and the <i>Oxford Universal</i> of 1933 agree on four primary meanings (the following from the <i>Webster’s</i> with examples removed):
</p>

<p>
Truth \Truth\, n.; pl. {Truths}. [OE. treuthe, trouthe, treowpe,
     AS. tre[&rsquo;o]w?. See {True}; cf. {Troth}, {Betroth}.]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li>The quality or being true; as:
(a) Conformity to fact or reality; exact accordance with
    that which is, or has been; or shall be.
(b) Conformity to rule; exactness; close correspondence
    with an example, mood, object of imitation, or the
    like.
(c) Fidelity; constancy; steadfastness; faithfulness.
(d) The practice of speaking what is true; freedom from
    falsehood; veracity.</li>
<li>That which is true or certain concerning any matter or
subject, or generally on all subjects; real state of
things; fact; verity; reality.</li>
<li>A true thing; a verified fact; a true statement or
proposition; an established principle, fixed law, or the
like; as, the great truths of morals.</li>
<li>Righteousness; true religion.</li>
</ol>

<p>
Very interesting (or maybe not at all interesting), but just why is this Sunday the day to bring up dictionaries and definitions of grand, overarching theoretical notions like “truth”?
</p>

<p>
Fair question. My point – and I do have one — is that I fiddled about with the tech to get this little corner of the Internet (as we used to say in the early ‘90s) two weeks ago and have said “Hello”, described the tech that I fiddled about with and dropped a few pithy quotes. Now what? What are we doing here? Will it be more of the same — a bit of technology, some brief quotes with no commentary, just a little of this and some of that? Or is there going to be a theme?
</p>

<p>
A theme — that’s the ticket! Truth would make a dandy theme — telling the truth (as I see it) about technology, dropping quotes that seem to be truthful, yes. And probably deeper into the weeds. That definition suggests that there’s a lot of leeway in truth as a topic: what are the facts; what is reality — really — what is, or has been, or shall be; what actually is conformity to — whatever; what does fidelity, constancy, steadfastness and faithrulness demand; and what are we called upon to speak — how do we avoid falseness?
</p>

<p>
Is that too pompous? Looking at the <i>Websters</i> again, there’s certainly some risk of pomposity in the second definition — we’ll have to be careful:
</p>

<p>
Pompous \Pomp&ldquo;ous\, a. [F. pompeux, L. pomposus. See {Pomp}.]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li>Displaying pomp; stately; showy with grandeur;
magnificent; as, a pompous procession.</li>
<li>Ostentatious; pretentious; boastful; vainlorious; as,
pompous manners; a pompous style.</li>
</ol>

<p>
On the other hand, it’s certainly something to aspire to — bringing a little truth into the discussion. We’ll just have to wait and see.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-23-what-is-truth.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-23-what-is-truth.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 13:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Science is Certain]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“If you thought that science was certain — well, that is just an error on your part.”—Richard P. Feynman, <i>The Quotable Feynman</i>, p. 349, Princeton University Press
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feynman.html">feynman</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[feynman]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-the-science-is-certain.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-the-science-is-certain.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 20:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[A Strange Superstition]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“The strange superstition has arisen in the Western world that we can start all over again, remaking human nature, human society, and the possibilities of happiness, as though the knowledge and experience of our ancestors were now entirely irrelevant.”—Sir Roger Scruton, <i>Becoming a Family</i>, <a href="https://www.city-journal.org/html/becoming-family-11806.html">City Journal</a>, Spring, 2001
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-foreign.html">foreign</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[foreign]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-a-strange-superstition.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-a-strange-superstition.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 13:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[News or PR?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“Journalism is printing what someone else does not want printed. Everything else is public relations.”—George Orwell — maybe, I can’t find a source — or maybe this:
</p>

<p>
“News is something somebody doesn’t want printed; all else is advertising.”—William Randolph Hearst — maybe, or maybe Lord Northcliffe (Alfred Harmsworth). Or maybe a whole <a href="https://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/01/20/news-suppress/">raft of others</a>.
</p>

<p>
Orwell seems to be joining Winston Churchill, Mark Twain, the Dalhi Lama, Dr. King and Albert Einstein as the go-to attribution for anything at all. Just remember that Abe Lincoln said, “You can’t trust anything you see on the Internet.” Or my Grandma Smith, “The paper holds still and you can write anything you want on it.”
</p>

<p>
At any rate, I’d say that there’s an awful lot of PR and advertising in the “newspapers” these days and precious little news/journalism. But that’s just my opinion, your mileage may vary.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-14-news-or-pr.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-14-news-or-pr.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 13:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[In Error]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“The first principle is that you must not fool yourself and you are the easiest person to fool.”—Richard P. Feynman
</p>

<p>
The first definition of falsehood (or Not Truth) in <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-30-what-is-falsehood.html">last week’s post</a> is: “Want of truth or accuracy; an untrue assertion or representation; error; misrepresentation; falsity.” This is simple error, free of dishonesty, evil intent or fabrication. I think I’m telling you (or myself) the truth, but I’m not.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-13-in-error.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-13-in-error.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Questions]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“I would rather have questions that can’t be answered than answers that can’t be questioned.”—Richard P. Feynman
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feynman.html">feynman</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[feynman]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-11-questions.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-11-questions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Tech Stuff]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Yesterday, in our “Hello World” post, I promised/threatened that I would someday get around to a) talking about why we dropped the Wordpress platform and b) talking about the tech behind the blog now.
</p>

<p>
Today I’ve been horsing around with the tech stuff, so that’s the topic that’s risen to the top for this post. The cream, if you will.
</p>

<p>
I mentioned Emacs and org-static-blog yesterday, so just a few words on each.
</p>

<p>
Emacs is perhaps the oldest “programmer’s text editor” in current use — it first saw the light of day in 1976, and its present incarnation has been in constant use since 1983.
</p>

<p>
I’ve used it off-and-on since the late ‘80s and I’ve done most of my writing with it since I retired (and no longer had to deliver work in Microsoft Word format!).
</p>

<p>
It’s not a “word processor” in the sense that it’s mainly just for putting letters “on the page” or into a file, although there are ways to suggest that the letters be bold, italic and the like. It’s frequently used to prepare text for publication by adding codes to the text that other tools interpret to then output “camera-ready copy”. And that’s about as far into the weeds as I’m willing to go on that topic just now. You’re welcome!
</p>

<p>
I also mentioned “org-static-blog” which highlights another side of Emacs, which is that it’s not only used to write software programs, but it’s also an environment for running software programs. In fact, it’s been, only partly facetiously, called an operating system that can also be used as a text editor.
</p>

<p>
It’s itself written in part in the programming language Lisp (another survivor, being the second oldest programming language still in regular use, having been first specified in 1958) and users can write programs in its eLisp that can either modify the way that Emacs looks and acts, making it incredibly flexible.
</p>

<p>
Emacs packages, as these eLisp programs are called, can also transform text that’s entered using Emacs. For example, an Emacs user could key in the content of a blog post like this one, then by running an eLisp package, have it saved as a new entry in a blog, with an entry on the blog’s home page, added to an archive page, an rss feed updated, and added to any appropriate tag lists. Basically everything that a platform like Wordpress or Blogger does while giving you, me, the end user, almost complete control.
</p>

<p>
That’s what org-static-blog does for this site. “org” for “org-mode” which is, well, this is already a long post, for now we’ll just say it’s one way to use Emacs. “static” for “static web site” - this blog isn’t a bunch of bits in a database that gets spit out and turned into web pages every time someone wants to view them. The web pages are generated once, and exist as individual files on a server - they’re “static”. And “blog” for, well, blog.
</p>

<p>
org-static-blog is written and maintained by <a href="https://bastibe.de">Bastian Bechtold</a>, a German software developer who develops software and makes it available for free - what we know as “Free Open Source Software” or FOSS. FOSS is yet another topic for another post, for now I’ll just link to <a href="https://github.com/bastibe/org-static-blog">org-static-blog online</a> and leave it at that.
</p>

<p>
I’ve spent much of my spare time yesterday and today getting things looking and working like this. It may evolve as time goes by — in fact, I can guarantee that it will, but for now, that’s the way it is, Monday, January 10, 2022. G’day.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-blogging.html">blogging</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-emacs.html">emacs</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-tech.html">tech</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[emacs]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[tech]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-10-tech-stuff.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-10-tech-stuff.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[About Us]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
This is a logical follow-on to years of noodling with hand-made sites in the early ‘90s, evolving into Wordpress sites that gradually got annoying (Wordpress, not the sites, at least not to me) that gave me a place to stash pithy quotes, clever asides and the occasional rant or essay.
</p>

<p>
It’s also a way to have yet another part of my digital world driven by emacs, specifically Bastian Bechtold’s org-static-blog.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-about.html">about</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[about]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/about.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/about.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Hello, World!]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
This is the first post for this new corner of the Web (doesn’t that sound just too, too 1990s?).
</p>

<p>
We shut down all of our old, Wordpress-based blogs about a year ago (just why will be a topic for another day) intending to fire them back up with some lighter-weight, open-source solution.
</p>

<p>
Well, those were the good intentions and we spent the rest of 2021 “paving the road to Hell” with those good intentions. Not really, we just got busy doing other things and didn’t get around to it.
</p>

<p>
Well, I got a friendly boot in the butt last Friday and here we are! I had a spare domain sitting around, “dasmith.xyz” and had been planning to play around with the Emacs-based org-static-blog package, and that boot was just enough to get things started.
</p>

<p>
More about the tech side of this is another topic for another day. As it is, it’s getting late and I’m keen on closing this down and hitting “Publish” and see what happens.
</p>

<p>
Bye for now.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-blogging.html">blogging</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-09-hello,-world!.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-09-hello,-world!.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 21:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
