<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></description>
<link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 21:54:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fourth Sunday in Lent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, we beseech thee, Almighty God, that we, who for our evil deeds do worthily deserve to be punished, by the comfort of thy grace may mercifully be relieved; through our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>

<p>
Laetare Sunday, <i>Rose</i> Vestments allowed.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-03-10-the-fourth-sunday-in-lent.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-03-10-the-fourth-sunday-in-lent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 21:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Third Sunday in Lent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
We beseech thee, Almighty God, look upon the hearty desires of thy humble servants, and stretch forth the right hand of thy Majesty, to be our defence against all our enemies; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-03-03-the-third-sunday-in-lent.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-03-03-the-third-sunday-in-lent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Second Sunday in Lent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who seest that we have no power of ourselves to help ourselves; Keep us both outwardly in our bodies, and inwardly in our souls; that we may be defended from all adversities which may happen to the body, and from all evil thoughts which may assault and hurt the soul; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>
.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-25-the-second-sunday-in-lent.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-25-the-second-sunday-in-lent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 07:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Matthias the Apostle]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who into the place of the traitor Judas didst choose thy faithful servant Matthias to be of the number of the twelve Apostles; Grant that thy Church, being alway preserved from false Apostles, may be ordered and guided by faithful and true pastors; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Red</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-24-st-matthias-the-apostle.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-24-st-matthias-the-apostle.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 22:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Ember Wednesday after Lent I]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who hast committed to the hands of men the ministry of reconciliation; We humbly beseech thee, by the inspiration of thy Holy Spirit, to put it into the hearts of many to offer themselves for this ministry; that thereby mankind may be drawn to thy blessed kingdom; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
ALMIGHTY and everlasting God, who hatest nothing that thou hast made, and dost forgive the sins of all those who are penitent; Create and make in us new and contrite hearts, that we, worthily lamenting our sins and acknowledging our wretchedness, may obtain of thee, the God of all mercy, perfect remission and forgiveness; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-21-ember-wednesday-after-lent-i.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-21-ember-wednesday-after-lent-i.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 07:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday in Lent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O LORD, who for our sake didst fast forty days and forty nights; Give us grace to use such abstinence, that, our flesh being subdued to the Spirit, we may ever obey thy godly motions in righteousness, and true holiness, to thy honour and glory, who livest and reignest with the Father and the Holy Ghost, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>. 
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-18-the-first-sunday-in-lent.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-18-the-first-sunday-in-lent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 07:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Ash Wednesday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY and everlasting God, who hatest nothing that thou hast made, and dost forgive the sins of all those who are penitent; Create and make in us new and contrite hearts, that we, worthily lamenting our sins and acknowledging our wretchedness, may obtain of thee, the God of all mercy, perfect remission and forgiveness; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-14-ash-wednesday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-14-ash-wednesday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 08:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Quinquagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O LORD, who hast taught us that all our doings without charity are nothing worth; Send thy Holy Ghost, and pour into our hearts that most excellent gift of charity, the very bond of peace and of all virtues, without which whosoever liveth is counted dead before thee. Grant this for thine only Son Jesus Christ&rsquo;s sake. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Pre-Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-pre-lent.html">Pre-Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Pre-Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-11-quinquagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-11-quinquagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 20:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Sexagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O Lord God, who seest that we put not our trust in any thing that we do; Mercifully grant that by thy power we may be defended against all adversity; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Pre-Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-pre-lent.html">Pre-Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Pre-Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-04-sexagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-04-sexagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 22:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Presentation of Christ, or Candlemas]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY and everliving God, we humbly beseech thy Majesty, that, as thy only-begotten Son was this day presented in the temple in substance of our flesh, so we may be presented unto thee with pure and clean hearts, by the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Pre-Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>White</i>.
</p>

<p>
Canadian journalist and Catholic blogger David Warren writes:
</p>

<p>
Today, the fortieth and last of Christmas, is once again “Candlemas.” It commemorates the presentation of the child Jesus in the Temple at Jerusalem, along with the sacrifice of Joseph and Mary, who could not afford a lamb. The feast also commemorates the conclusion of the forty-day cycle for the purification of a mother, according to Hebraic custom. A poor Jewish couple with their firstborn, acting according to ancient Mosaic law; greeted by Anne, and by the prophetic Simeon, who utters the <i>Nunc Dimittis</i>:
</p>

<p>
“Lord, now lettest thou thy servant depart in peace, according to thy word. For mine eyes have seen thy salvation, which thou hast prepared before the face of all people; a light to lighten the Gentiles, and the glory of thy people Israel.”
</p>

<p>
I was an Anglican too many years to abandon this splendid English rendering of the Scripture, the third of Saint Luke’s great canticles (after the Magnificat and the Benedictus). The Latin is good and the Greek is better. The poetry of the words is fully necessary. They are intended to convey the poignancy of the scene, in the face of this old man, who has recognized his Messiah, to the amazement of the child’s own parents.
</p>

<p>
It was from this canticle that the Greeks named the feast, Hypapante, referring to this moment of recognition by the Old, of the New. Tired and waiting for death, standing himself at the junction of worlds, the eyes of Simeon see that nothing will be the same. The Messiah has come, and the whole course of history that must follow flickers in the old man’s eyes, still bound in the breath of a moment to this blessed Earth, and the dimension of Time. It is the canticle I read over my own father’s grave, as we committed him, dust to dust.
</p>

<p>
There is, I am sure, theological significance in each of the events that combine to be celebrated within Candlemas — in the procession and the blessing of the candles. The fulfilment of that ancient law, drawn from the pages of Leviticus, is again before us.
</p>

<p>
I like to think on the two turtle doves: the gift to the Temple that this couple, Joseph and Mary, could actually afford. The simplicity of it, alongside the incomprehensible gift of Jesus.
</p>

<p>
Christ has come to fulfil the laws of Moses, and the Law behind all law. It makes no sense that He should be here, that He should arrive in this human form, in the arms of this young mother. The ancient imagination demanded that a Saviour come in timpani and trumpets. Here is this small child, and these impoverished parents, with their brace of pigeons in a stick cage. They stand at the intersection of all Time.
</p>

<p>
The Author of all we know, has sent so personal a Gift, by such messengers, as the fulfilment of His promise to Abraham. I find this astonishing; indeed, too preposterous not to be true. That He is presenting Himself, helpless at the Temple, in fulfilment of an ancient vow. I find it very odd. For what does this gesture suggest?
</p>

<p>
The humility of a Lover.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feast.html">feast</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-pre-lent.html">Pre-Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feast]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Pre-Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-02-the-presentation-of-christ.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-02-02-the-presentation-of-christ.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 22:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Septuagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O LORD, we beseech thee favourably to hear the prayers of thy people; that we, who are justly punished for our offences, may be mercifully delivered by thy goodness, for the glory of thy Name; through Jesus Christ our Saviour, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Ghost ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Pre-Lent, the liturgical color of the day is <i>Purple</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-pre-lent.html">Pre-Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Pre-Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-28-septuagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-28-septuagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 07:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Conversion of St Paul]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who, through the preaching of the blessed Apostle Saint Paul, hast caused the light of the Gospel to shine throughout the world; Grant, we beseech thee, that we, having his wonderful conversion in remembrance, may show forth our thankfulness unto thee for the same, by following the holy doctrine which he taught; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Epiphany, the liturgical color of the day is <i>White</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-epiphany.html">Epiphany</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-25-the-conversion-of-st-paul.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-25-the-conversion-of-st-paul.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Ezekiel 33:1-9]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Again the word of the LORD came unto me, saying, Son of man, speak to the children of thy people, and say unto them, When I bring the sword upon a land, if the people of the land take a man of their coasts, and set him for their watchman: If when he seeth the sword come upon the land, he blow the trumpet, and warn the people; Then whosoever heareth the sound of the trumpet, and taketh not warning; if the sword come, and take him away, his blood shall be upon his own head. He heard the sound of the trumpet, and took not warning; his blood shall be upon him. But he that taketh warning shall deliver his soul.
</p>

<p>
But if the watchman see the sword come, and blow not the trumpet, and the people be not warned; if the sword come, and take any person from among them, he is taken away in his iniquity; but his blood will I require at the watchman&rsquo;s hand.
</p>

<p>
So thou, O son of man, I have set thee a watchman unto the house of Israel; therefore thou shalt hear the word at my mouth, and warn them from me. When I say unto the wicked, O wicked man, thou shalt surely die; if thou dost not speak to warn the wicked from his way, that wicked man shall die in his iniquity; but his blood will I require at thine hand.
</p>

<p>
Nevertheless, if thou warn the wicked of his way to turn from it; if he do not turn from his way, he shall die in his iniquity; but thou hast delivered thy soul.
</p>

<p>
&#x2026;.
</p>

<p>
This is the first lesson for Evensong on the Tuesday after the 3rd Sunday after Epiphany. It raises the question what it means for those of us who are not a “man of the coast” whom the people of the land have set up for their watchman. If we are inland and anonymous to our fellows and see the sword coming upon the land, are we called upon to sound the trumpet? Is this solely speaking to capital-P Prophets like Ezekiel? Or perhaps only to the Ezekiel who lived in Nippur in the 6th century B.C.?
</p>

<p>
If I am a Christian living in the 21st century A.D., doing my best, or at least trying somewhat, to do God’s will, and I see what seems to be a sword (or a large variety of swords), am I called to ignore it/them and carry on with my daily tasks, or am I called in some way to “sound the trumpet”?
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-readings.html">readings</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[readings]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-23-ezekiel-33:1-9.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-23-ezekiel-33:1-9.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 12:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Third Sunday after Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY and everlasting God, mercifully look upon our infirmities, and in all our dangers and necessities stretch forth thy right hand to help and defend us; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
he Season is Epiphany. The liturgical color of the day is <i>Green</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-epiphany.html">Epiphany</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-21-the-third-sunday-after-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-21-the-third-sunday-after-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 06:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Second Sunday After Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY and everlasting God, who dost govern all things in heaven and earth; Mercifully hear the supplications of thy people, and grant us thy peace all the days of our life; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Epiphany. The liturgical color of the day is <i>Green</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-epiphany.html">Epiphany</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-14-the-second-sunday-after-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-14-the-second-sunday-after-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 09:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday After Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O LORD, we beseech thee mercifully to receive the prayers of thy people who call upon thee; and grant that they may both perceive and know what things they ought to do, and also may have grace and power faithfully to fulfil the same; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Epiphany, within the Octave of Epiphany. The liturgical color of the day is <i>White</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-epiphany.html">Epiphany</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-07-the-first-sunday-after-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-07-the-first-sunday-after-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 16:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who by the leading of a star didst manifest thy only-begotten Son to the Gentiles; Mercifully grant that we, who know thee now by faith, may after this life have the fruition of thy glorious Godhead; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Epiphany, the liturgical color of the day is <i>White</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-epiphany.html">Epiphany</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-06-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-06-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 22:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[I John 4]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Beloved, believe not every spirit, but try the spirits whether they are of God: because many false prophets are gone out into the world. Hereby know ye the Spirit of God: Every spirit that confesseth that Jesus Christ is come in the flesh is of God: And every spirit that confesseth not that Jesus Christ is come in the flesh is not of God: and this is that spirit of antichrist, whereof ye have heard that it should come; and even now already is it in the world.
</p>

<p>
Ye are of God, little children, and have overcome them: because greater is he that is in you, than he that is in the world. They are of the world: therefore speak they of the world, and the world heareth them. We are of God: he that knoweth God heareth us; he that is not of God heareth not us. Hereby know we the spirit of truth, and the spirit of error.
</p>

<p>
Beloved, let us love one another: for love is of God; and every one that loveth is born of God, and knoweth God. He that loveth not knoweth not God; for God is love. In this was manifested the love of God toward us, because that God sent his only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through him. Herein is love, not that we loved God, but that he loved us, and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins.
</p>

<p>
Beloved, if God so loved us, we ought also to love one another. No man hath seen God at any time. If we love one another, God dwelleth in us, and his love is perfected in us. Hereby know we that we dwell in him, and he in us, because he hath given us of his Spirit. And we have seen and do testify that the Father sent the Son to be the Saviour of the world.
</p>

<p>
Whosoever shall confess that Jesus is the Son of God, God dwelleth in him, and he in God. And we have known and believed the love that God hath to us. God is love; and he that dwelleth in love dwelleth in God, and God in him. Herein is our love made perfect, that we may have boldness in the day of judgment: because as he is, so are we in this world.
</p>

<p>
There is no fear in love; but perfect love casteth out fear: because fear hath torment. He that feareth is not made perfect in love. We love him, because he first loved us. If a man say, I love God, and hateth his brother, he is a liar: for he that loveth not his brother whom he hath seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen? And this commandment have we from him, That he who loveth God love his brother also. 
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-readings.html">readings</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[readings]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-04-i-john-4.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-04-i-john-4.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 06:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Circumcision of Christ]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who madest thy blessed Son to be circumcised, and obedient to the law for man; Grant us the true circumcision of the Spirit; that, our hearts, and all our members, being mortified from all worldly and carnal lusts, we may in all things obey thy blessed will; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, within the Octave of Christmas, the Liturgical Color is <i>White</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-01-the-circumcision-of-christ.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2024-01-01-the-circumcision-of-christ.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday After Christmas]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who hast given us thy only-begotten Son to take our nature upon him, and as at this time to be born of a pure virgin; Grant that we being regenerate, and made thy children by adoption and grace, may daily be renewed by thy Holy Spirit; through the same our Lord Jesus Christ, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the same Spirit ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, within the Octave of Christmas, the Liturgical Color is <i>White</i>. 
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-christmastide.html">Christmastide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Christmastide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-31-the-first-sunday-after-christmas.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-31-the-first-sunday-after-christmas.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[December 30, 2023]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
I am leading you along a way that is uniquely right for you. The closer to Me you grow, the more fully you become your true self—the one I designed you to be. Because you are one of a kind, the path you are traveling with Me diverges increasingly from that of other people. However, in My mysterious wisdom and ways, I enable you to follow this solitary path while staying in close contact with others. In fact, the more completely you devote yourself to Me, the more freely you can love people.
</p>

<p>
Marvel at the beauty of a life intertwined with My Presence. Rejoice as we journey together in intimate communion. Enjoy the adventure of finding yourself through losing yourself in Me.
</p>

<p>
<i>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation; the old has gone, the new has come!</i> — 2 Corinthians 5:17
</p>

<p>
<i>For we are God’s workmanship, created in Christ Jesus to do good works, which God prepared in advance for us to do.</i> — Ephesians 3:10
</p>

<p>
<i>Dear friends, let us love one another, for love comes from God. Everyone who loves has been born of God and knows God. Whoever does not love does not know God, because God is love.</i> — 1 John 4:7-8
</p>

<p>
<i>”Remain in me, and I will remain in you. No branch can bear fruit by itself; it must remain in the vine. Neither can you bear fruit unless you remain in me.”</i> — John 15:4
</p>

<p>
Found in <i>Jesus Calling</i> by Sarah Young
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-30-december-30,-2023.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-30-december-30,-2023.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 09:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Thomas á Becket, Bishop and Martyr]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who gave the Martyr Saint Thomas á Becket the courage to give up his life for the sake of justice, grant, through his intercession, that, renouncing our life for the sake of Christ in this world, we may find it in heaven. Through our Lord Jesus Christ, your Son, who lives and reigns with you in the unity of the Holy Spirit, God, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, within the Octave of Christmas, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-29-st-thomas-a-becket,-bishop-and-martyr.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-29-st-thomas-a-becket,-bishop-and-martyr.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 06:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Holy Innocents]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who out of the mouths of babes and sucklings hast ordained strength, and madest infants to glorify thee by their deaths; Mortify and kill all vices in us, and so strengthen us by thy grace, that by the innocency of our lives, and constancy of our faith even unto death, we may glorify thy holy Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, within the Octave of Christmas, the Liturgical Color is <i>Red</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-28-the-holy-innocents.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-28-the-holy-innocents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 09:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St John, Apostle and Evangelist]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
MERCIFUL Lord, we beseech thee to cast thy bright beams of light upon thy Church, that it, being illumined by the doctrine of thy blessed Apostle and Evangelist Saint John, may so walk in the light of thy truth, that it may at length attain to life everlasting; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, within the Octave of Christmas, the Liturgical Color is <i>White</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-27-st-john,-apostle-and-evangelist.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-27-st-john,-apostle-and-evangelist.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 12:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Stephen, Martyr and Deacon]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, O Lord, that, in all our sufferings here upon earth for the testimony of thy truth, we may stedfastly look up to heaven, and by faith behold the glory that shall be revealed; and, being filled with the Holy Ghost, may learn to love and bless our persecutors by the example of thy first Martyr Saint Stephen, who prayed for his murderers to thee, O blessed Jesus, who standest at the right hand of God to succour all those who suffer for thee, our only Mediator and Advocate. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-26-st-stephen-martyr-and-deacon.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-26-st-stephen-martyr-and-deacon.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 10:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Christmas Day]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who hast given us thy only-begotten Son to take our nature upon him, and as at this time to be born of a pure virgin; Grant that we being regenerate, and made thy children by adoption and grace, may daily be renewed by thy Holy Spirit; through the same our Lord Jesus Christ, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the same Spirit ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Christmastide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-christmastide.html">Christmastide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Christmastide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-25-christmas-day.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-25-christmas-day.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 09:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Christmas Proclamation]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Nativity of our Lord Jesus Christ
</p>

<p>
The Twenty-fifth Day of December,
</p>

<p>
when ages beyond number had run their course from the creation of the world,
</p>

<p>
when God in the beginning created heaven and earth, and formed man in his own likeness;
</p>

<p>
when century upon century had passed since the Almighty set his bow in the clouds after the Great Flood, as a sign of covenant and peace;
</p>

<p>
in the twenty-first century since Abraham, our father in faith, came out of Ur of the Chaldees;
</p>

<p>
in the thirteenth century since the People of Israel were led by Moses in the Exodus from Egypt;
</p>

<p>
around the thousandth year since David was anointed King;
</p>

<p>
in the sixty-fifth week of the prophecy of Daniel;
</p>

<p>
in the one hundred and ninety-fourth Olympiad;
</p>

<p>
in the year seven hundred and fifty-two since the foundation of the City of Rome;
</p>

<p>
in the forty-second year of the reign of Caesar Octavian Augustus, the whole world being at peace,
</p>

<p>
JESUS CHRIST, eternal God and Son of the eternal Father, desiring to consecrate the world by his most loving presence, was conceived by the Holy Spirit, and when nine months had passed since his conception, was born of the Virgin Mary in Bethlehem of Judah, and was made man:
</p>

<p>
The Nativity of Our Lord Jesus Christ according to the flesh.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-christmastide.html">Christmastide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Christmastide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-25-christmas-proclamation.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-25-christmas-proclamation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 05:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fourth Sunday in Advent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O LORD, raise up, we pray thee, thy power, and come among us, and with great might succour us; that whereas, through our sins and wickedness, we are sore let and hindered in running the race that is set before us, thy bountiful grace and mercy may speedily help and deliver us; through Jesus Christ our Lord, to whom, with thee and the Holy Ghost, be honour and glory, world without end. <i>Amen.</i>
</p>

<p>
The Season is Advent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-advent.html">Advent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Advent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-24-the-fourth-sunday-in-advent.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-24-the-fourth-sunday-in-advent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 21:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Saturday Ember Day]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who hast committed to the hands of men the ministry of reconciliation; We humbly beseech thee, by the inspiration of thy Holy Spirit, to put it into the hearts of many to offer themselves for this ministry; that thereby mankind may be drawn to thy blessed kingdom; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Advent, the Liturgical Color is Purple. 
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-advent.html">Advent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Advent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-23-saturday-ember-day.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-23-saturday-ember-day.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 19:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Friday Ember Day]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who hast committed to the hands of men the ministry of reconciliation; We humbly beseech thee, by the inspiration of thy Holy Spirit, to put it into the hearts of many to offer themselves for this ministry; that thereby mankind may be drawn to thy blessed kingdom; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Advent, the Liturgical Color is Purple. 
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-advent.html">Advent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Advent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-22-friday-ember-day.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-12-22-friday-ember-day.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 20:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
