<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></description>
<link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 10:59:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Tuesday in Witsun Week]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, we beseech thee, merciful God, that thy Church, being gathered together in unity by thy Holy Spirit, may manifest thy power among all peoples, to the glory of thy Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the same Spirit, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Pentecost (Whitsunday)
</p>

<p>
O GOD, who as at this time didst teach the hearts of thy faithful people, by sending to them the light of thy Holy Spirit; Grant us by the same Spirit to have a right judgment in all things, and evermore to rejoice in his holy comfort; through the merits of Christ Jesus our Saviour, who liveth and reigneth with thee, in the unity of the same Spirit, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Whitsuntide, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-whitsuntide.html">Whitsuntide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Whitsuntide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-30-tuesday-in-witsun-week.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-30-tuesday-in-witsun-week.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 10:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Monday in Whitsun Week]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
SEND, we beseech thee, Almighty God, thy Holy Spirit into our hearts, that he may direct and rule us according to thy will, comfort us in all our afflictions, defend us from all error, and lead us into all truth; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who with thee and the same Holy Spirit liveth and reigneth, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Pentecost (Whitsunday)
</p>

<p>
O GOD, who as at this time didst teach the hearts of thy faithful people, by sending to them the light of thy Holy Spirit; Grant us by the same Spirit to have a right judgment in all things, and evermore to rejoice in his holy comfort; through the merits of Christ Jesus our Saviour, who liveth and reigneth with thee, in the unity of the same Spirit, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Whitsuntide, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-whitsuntide.html">Whitsuntide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Whitsuntide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-29-monday-in-whitsun-week.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-29-monday-in-whitsun-week.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 10:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Pentecost, Commonly Called Whitsuntide]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O God, who as at this time didst teach the hearts of thy faithful people, by sending to them the light of thy Holy Spirit; Grant us by the same Spirit to have a right judgment in all things, and evermore to rejoice in his holy comfort; through the merits of Christ Jesus our Saviour, who liveth and reigneth with thee, in the unity of the same Spirit, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Whitsuntide, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-whitsuntide.html">Whitsuntide</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[Whitsuntide]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-28-pentecost,-commonly-called-whitsuntide.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-28-pentecost,-commonly-called-whitsuntide.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 10:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Augustine of Canterbury]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who didst vouchsafe to give blessed Augustine thy Bishop to be the first teacher of the English people; grant, we beseech thee, that we who on earth proclaim his merits, may inwardly percieve the benefit of his prayers for us on high. Through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Ascensiontide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-26-st-augustine-of-canterbury.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-26-st-augustine-of-canterbury.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 15:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Vincent of Lèrins]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who didst raise up thy blessed Confessor Vincent to proclaim the rule of faith; grant that all thy people may steadfastly witness to the fullness of Catholic truths, that the same may be received everywhere, always, and by all, even as thou has taught us. Through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Ascensiontide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
Saint Vincent of Lérins, pseudonym Peregrinus, (born, possibly Toul, Belgica [now in France]—died c. 450; feast day May 24), Gallo-Roman saint, the chief theologian of the Abbey of Lérins, known especially for his heresiography Commonitoria (“Memoranda”).
</p>

<p>
Early in the treatise he established his oft-quoted and influential principle on tradition as the test of orthodoxy—the true Catholic faith is that which has been “believed everywhere, always and by all.” This has been quoted often in support of Anglicanism’s claim to be a <i>via media</i>. Listen to Vincent’s voice on the subject:
</p>

<p>
“I have often earnestly inquired of many holy and learned men how and by what sure and universal rule I may distinguish the truth of the Catholic faith from the falsehood of heresy. In almost every instance I have received this answer: All who wish to detect the frauds of heretics and to stay rooted in the Catholic faith must, with the Lord’s help, fortify their own belief in two ways: first by the authority of Scripture, and then, by the tradition of the Catholic Church.
</p>

<p>
“Since the canon of Scripture is complete and more than sufficient of itself for everything, you might ask what need is there to join with it the authority of the church’s interpretation. For this reason: Because owing to the depth of holy Scripture, all do not accept it in one and the same sense. But one understands its words in one way, another differently, so that the Bible seems to be capable of as many interpretations as there are interpreters. Thus it is very necessary that the rule for the right understanding of the prophets and apostles should be framed in accordance with the standard ecclesiastical and Catholic interpretation.
</p>

<p>
“ <i>Moreover, in the Catholic Church itself, all possible care must be taken that we hold that faith which has been believed everywhere, always and by all.</i> This rule we shall observe if we follow universality, antiquity and consent. We follow universality if we confess that one faith as true that the whole church throughout the world confesses. Antiquity, if we never depart from those interpretations manifestly held by our holy ancestors and fathers. Consent, if in antiquity itself, we adhere to the definitions and determinations held by all, or at least by almost all priests and teachers.”
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-24-st-vincent-of-lerins.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-24-st-vincent-of-lerins.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 16:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Sunday After Ascension]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, the King of glory, who hast exalted thine only Son Jesus Christ with great triumph unto thy kingdom in heaven; We beseech thee, leave us not comfortless; but send to us thine Holy Ghost to comfort us, and exalt us unto the same place whither our Saviour Christ is gone before, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the same Holy Ghost, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Ascensiontide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-ascensiontide.html">Ascensiontide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Ascensiontide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-21-the-sunday-after-ascension.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-21-the-sunday-after-ascension.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Ascension Day]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, we beseech thee, Almighty God, that like as we do believe thy only-begotten Son our Lord Jesus Christ to have ascended into the heavens; so we may also in heart and mind thither ascend, and with him continually dwell, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Ghost, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Ascensiontide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
And he said unto them, These are the words which I spake unto you, while I was yet with you, that all things must be fulfilled, which were written in the law of Moses, and in the prophets, and in the psalms, concerning me. Then opened he their understanding, that they might understand the scriptures, And said unto them, Thus it is written, and thus it behoved Christ to suffer, and to rise from the dead the third day: And that repentance and remission of sins should be preached in his name among all nations, beginning at Jerusalem. And ye are witnesses of these things. And, behold, I send the promise of my Father upon you: but tarry ye in the city of Jerusalem, until ye be endued with power from on high. And he led them out as far as to Bethany, and he lifted up his hands, and blessed them. And it came to pass, while he blessed them, he was parted from them, and carried up into heaven. And they worshipped him, and returned to Jerusalem with great joy: And were continually in the temple, praising and blessing God. Amen.— <i>St Luke 24:44</i>
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-ascensiontide.html">Ascensiontide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Ascensiontide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-18-ascension-day.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-18-ascension-day.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fifth Sunday After Easter, Commonly Called Rogation Sunday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O Lord, from whom all good things do come; Grant to us thy humble servants, that by thy holy inspiration we may think those things that are good, and by thy merciful guiding may perform the same; through our Lord Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
“Rogation” comes from the Latin verb <i>rogare</i>, meaning “to ask”. There are two phases of Rogation Days, the “major” on 25 April, and the “minor”, Monday through Wednesday before Ascension Thursday.
</p>

<p>
On Rogation Days, with fasting, processions and the singing of the Litany of Saints, we ask God to protect us from danger. One danger in the ancient world was crop failure. Indeed, our Christian Rogation Days tradition stems from the pagan Roman practice of the Robigalia procession on 25 April with, among other weird things, the sacrifice of a dog to the god (really a demon) Robigus against wheat rust, a disease that attacked that precious crop. By the 5th century here and there in France, Christians had replaced all the pagan stuff with goodly uses. The practice spread in a wholesome way as wholesome practices did. Pope Leo III (+816) incorporated the Rogation Days into the Roman Rite. So, we’ve had them for well over a thousand years, give or take a century.
</p>

<p>
<i>Notes on Rogation taken from <a href="https://onepeterfive.com/5th-sunday-after-easter-lies/">onepeter5.com</a></i>
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-14-the-fifth-sunday-after-easter,-commonly-called-rogation-sunday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-14-the-fifth-sunday-after-easter,-commonly-called-rogation-sunday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 22:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fourth Sunday After Easter]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who alone canst order the unruly wills and affections of sinful men; Grant unto thy people, that they may love the thing which thou commandest, and desire that which thou dost promise; that so, among the sundry and manifold changes of the world, our hearts may surely there be fixed, where true joys are to be found; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-07-the-fourth-sunday-after-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-07-the-fourth-sunday-after-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 08:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Philip and St James, Apostles]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, whom truly to know is everlasting life; Grant us perfectly to know thy Son Jesus Christ to be the way, the truth, and the life; that, following the steps of thy holy Apostles, Saint Philip and Saint James, we may stedfastly walk in the way that leadeth to eternal life; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-01-st-philip-and-st-james,-apostles.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-05-01-st-philip-and-st-james,-apostles.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Third Sunday After Easter]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who showest to them that are in error the light of thy truth, to the intent that they may return into the way of righteousness; Grant unto all those who are admitted into the fellowship of Christ&rsquo;s Religion, that they may avoid those things that are contrary to their profession, and follow all such things as are agreeable to the same; through our Lord Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
Today is also the Feast of St Catherine of Siena, Saint, Doctor of the Church, Patroness of Italy,
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-30-the-third-sunday-after-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-30-the-third-sunday-after-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 08:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Mark's Day]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who hast instructed thy holy Church with the heavenly doctrine of thy Evangelist Saint Mark; Give us grace that, being not like children carried away with every blast of vain doctrine, we may be established in the truth of thy holy Gospel; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-25-st-mark's-day.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-25-st-mark's-day.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 08:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Second Sunday After Easter, Commonly Called Good Shepherd Sunday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who hast given thine only Son to be unto us both a sacrifice for sin, and also an ensample of godly life; Give us grace that we may always most thankfully receive that his inestimable benefit, and also daily endeavour ourselves to follow the blessed steps of his most holy life; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-23-the-second-sunday-after-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-23-the-second-sunday-after-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 10:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday After Easter, Commonly Called Doubting Thomas Sunday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY Father, who hast given thine only Son to die for our sins, and to rise again for our justification; Grant us so to put away the leaven of malice and wickedness, that we may always serve thee in pureness of living and truth; through the merits of the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-16-the-first-sunday-after-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-16-the-first-sunday-after-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 09:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Saturday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, we beseech thee, Almighty God, that we who have devoutly kept the Paschal Feast, may thereby be counted worthy to attain unto eternal joys, Through the same our Lord Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
Note: <i>See the note to this year’s Easter Wednesday for this Collect’s source</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-15-easter-saturday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-15-easter-saturday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 19:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Friday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY, everlasting God, who hast conferred the Paschal Mystery upon mankind for a covenant of reconciliation: grant unto our souls that what we celebrate with our lips, we may effectually show forth in our lives. Through the same our Lord Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
Also the Feast of St Justin Martyr
</p>

<p>
Note: <i>See the note to this year’s Easter Wednesday for this Collect’s source</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-14-easter-friday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-14-easter-friday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 15:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Thursday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who hast knit together divers nations in the one confession of thy Name: grant that they who have been born again in the font of Baptism, may likewise be one in inward faith and holiness of conversation. Through the same our Lord Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
Note: <i>See the note to this year’s Easter Wednesday for this Collect’s source</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-13-easter-thursday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-13-easter-thursday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 16:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Wednesday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, who makest us glad by the yearly solemnity of our Lord’s Resurrection: mercifully grant,that in keeping of these temporal feasts, we may hereafter attain to the joys of everlasting life. Through the same, our Lord Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>

<p>
Note: <i>This collect is not found in the 1662 Book of Common Prayer. It is taken from the American “The Anglican Office Book” originally developed by Fr Paul Hartzell in 1944. Text found there which is not found in the American Book of Common Prayer (1928) or the British Book of Common Prayer (1662) is presumably based on one of the versions of the Sarum Rite or some other pre-Protestant form</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-12-easter-wednesday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-12-easter-wednesday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Tuesday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, we beseech thee, Almighty God, that we who celebrate with reverence the Paschal feast, may be found worthy to attain to everlasting joys; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-11-easter-tuesday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-11-easter-tuesday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 09:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Monday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O GOD, whose blessed Son did manifest himself to his disciples in the breaking of bread; Open, we pray thee, the eyes of our faith, that we may behold thee in all thy works; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-10-easter-monday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-10-easter-monday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Easter Sunday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, who through thine only-begotten Son Jesus Christ hast overcome death, and opened unto us the gate of everlasting life; We humbly beseech thee that, as by thy special grace preventing us thou dost put into our minds good desires, so by thy continual help we may bring the same to good effect; through the same Jesus Christ our Lord, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Ghost ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Eastertide, the Liturgical Color is White.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-eastertide.html">Eastertide</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-09-easter-sunday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-09-easter-sunday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 15:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Saturday Before Easter, Commonly Called Holy Saturday or Easter Even]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
GRANT, O Lord, that as we are baptized into the death of thy blessed Son, our Saviour Jesus Christ, so by continual mortifying our corrupt affections we may be buried with him; and that through the grave, and gate of death, we may pass to our joyful resurrection; for his merits, who died, and was buried, and rose again for us, the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-08-the-saturday-before-easter,-commonly-called-holy-saturday-or-easter-even.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-08-the-saturday-before-easter,-commonly-called-holy-saturday-or-easter-even.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 15:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Friday Before Easter, Commonly Called Good Friday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, we beseech thee graciously to behold this thy family, for which our Lord Jesus Christ was contented to be betrayed, and given up into the hands of wicked men, and to suffer death upon the cross; who now liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Ghost ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
ALMIGHTY and everlasting God, by whose Spirit the whole body of the Church is governed and sanctified; Receive our supplications and prayers, which we offer before thee for all estates of men in thy holy Church, that every member of the same, in his vocation and ministry, may truly and godly serve thee; through our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
MERCIFUL God, who hast made all men, and hatest nothing that thou hast made, nor desirest the death of a sinner, but rather that he should be converted and live; Have mercy upon all who know thee not as thou art revealed in the Gospel of thy Son. Take from them all ignorance, hardness of heart, and contempt of thy Word; and so fetch them home, blessed Lord, to thy fold, that they may be made one flock under one shepherd, Jesus Christ our Lord, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Spirit, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Proper Sentences for Good Friday are as follows:
</p>

<p>
Is it nothing to you, all ye that pass by? behold, and see if there be any sorrow like unto my sorrow which is done unto me, wherewith the LORD hath afflicted me. <i>Lam. i. I 2</i>.
</p>

<p>
In whom we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, according to the riches of his grace. <i>Eph. i. 7</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-07-the-friday-before-easter,-commonly-called-good-friday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-07-the-friday-before-easter,-commonly-called-good-friday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 13:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Thursday Before Easter, Commonly Called Maundy Thursday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY Father, whose dear Son, on the night before he suffered, did institute the Sacrament of his Body and Blood; Mercifully grant that we may thankfully receive the same in remembrance of him, who in these holy mysteries giveth us a pledge of life eternal; the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord, who now liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Spirit ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-06-the-thursday-before-easter,-commonly-called-maundy-thursday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-06-the-thursday-before-easter,-commonly-called-maundy-thursday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 14:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Wednesday Before Easter]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ASSIST us mercifully with thy help, O Lord God of our salvation; that we may enter with joy upon the meditation of those mighty acts, whereby thou hast given unto us life and immortality; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-05-the-wednesday-before-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-05-the-wednesday-before-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 08:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Tuesday Before Easter]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O LORD God, whose blessed Son, our Saviour, gave his back to the smiters and hid not his face from shame; Grant us grace to take joyfully the sufferings of the present time, in full assurance of the glory that shall be revealed; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-04-the-tuesday-before-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-04-the-tuesday-before-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 06:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Monday Before Easter]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
ALMIGHTY God, whose most dear Son went not up to joy but first he suffered pain, and entered not into glory before he was crucified; Mercifully grant that we, walking in the way of the cross, may find it none other than the way of life and peace; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-03-the-monday-before-easter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-03-the-monday-before-easter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 22:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Sunday Next Before Easter, Commonly Called Palm Sunday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Almighty and everlasting God, who, of thy tender love towards mankind, hast sent thy Son, our Saviour Jesus Christ, to take upon him our flesh, and to suffer death upon the cross, that all mankind should follow the example of his great humility; Mercifully grant, that we may both follow the example of his patience, and also be made partakers of his resurrection; through the same Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-02-the-sunday-next-before-easter,-commonly-called-palm-sunday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-04-02-the-sunday-next-before-easter,-commonly-called-palm-sunday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 15:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fifth Sunday in Lent, Commonly Called Passion Sunday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
We beseech thee, Almighty God, mercifully to look upon thy people; that by thy great goodness they may be governed and preserved evermore, both in body and soul; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Passiontide, the two weeks ending on Holy Saturday commemorating the Passion of Christ, begins today.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-03-26-the-fifth-sunday-in-lent,-commonly-called-passion-sunday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-03-26-the-fifth-sunday-in-lent,-commonly-called-passion-sunday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 15:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Anunciation of the BVM]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
And in the sixth month the angel Gabriel was sent from God unto a city of Galilee, named Nazareth, to a virgin espoused to a man whose name was Joseph, of the house of David; and the virgin&rsquo;s name was Mary.
</p>

<p>
And the angel came in unto her, and said, Hail, thou that art highly favoured, the Lord is with thee: blessed art thou among women.
</p>

<p>
And when she saw him, she was troubled at his saying, and cast in her mind what manner of salutation this should be.
</p>

<p>
And the angel said unto her, Fear not, Mary: for thou hast found favour with God.
</p>

<p>
And, behold, thou shalt conceive in thy womb, and bring forth a son, and shalt call his name JESUS.
</p>

<p>
He shall be great, and shall be called the Son of the Highest: and the Lord God shall give unto him the throne of his father David: and he shall reign over the house of Jacob for ever; and of his kingdom there shall be no end.
</p>

<p>
Then said Mary unto the angel, How shall this be, seeing I know not a man? And the angel answered and said unto her, The Holy Ghost shall come upon thee, and the power of the Highest shall overshadow thee: therefore also that holy thing which shall be born of thee shall be called the Son of God.
</p>

<p>
And, behold, thy cousin Elisabeth, she hath also conceived a son in her old age: and this is the sixth month with her, who was called barren.
</p>

<p>
For with God nothing shall be impossible.
</p>

<p>
And Mary said, Behold the handmaid of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word. And the angel departed from her.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feasts.html">feasts</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[feasts]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-03-25-anunciation-of-the-bvm.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-03-25-anunciation-of-the-bvm.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
