<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[David's Ramblings]]></description>
<link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 20:54:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St David of Wales]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O God, you gave your servant David the virtue of wisdom and the gift of eloquence, and made him an example of prayer and pastoral zeal; grant that, through his intercession, your Church may ever prosper and render you joyful praise. We ask this through our Lord Jesus Christ, your Son, who lives and reigns with you in the unity of the Holy Spirit, God for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-03-01-st-david-of-wales.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-03-01-st-david-of-wales.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 20:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday in Lent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O Lord, who for our sake didst fast forty days and forty nights; Give us grace to use such abstinence, that, our flesh being subdued to the Spirit, we may ever obey thy godly motions in righteousness, and true holiness, to thy honour and glory, who livest and reignest with the Father and the Holy Ghost, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the Liturgical Color is Purple
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-26-the-first-sunday-in-lent.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-26-the-first-sunday-in-lent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 12:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[St Matthias]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
O ALMIGHTY God, who into the place of the traitor Judas didst choose thy faithful servant Matthias to be of the number of the twelve Apostles; Grant that thy Church, being alway preserved from false Apostles, may be ordered and guided by faithful and true pastors; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent. The Liturgical color of the day is Red.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-24-st-matthias.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-24-st-matthias.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 05:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Ash Wednesday Commination]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
A Commination or Denouncing of God’s Anger and Judgments Against Sinners
</p>

<p>
With certain prayers to be used on the first day of Lent, and at other times, as the Ordinary shall appoint.
</p>

<p>
<i>After Morning Prayer, the Litany ended, according to the accustomed manner, the Priest shall in the reading Pew or Pulpit say</i>,
</p>

<p>
BRETHREN, in the primitive Church there was a godly discipline, that, at the beginning of Lent, such persons as stood convicted of notorious sin were put to open penance, and punished in this world, that their souls might be saved in the day of the Lord; and that others, admonished by their example, might be the more afraid to offend.
</p>

<p>
Instead whereof, until the said discipline may be restored again, (which is much to be wished,) it is thought good that at this time (in the presence of you all) should be read the general sentences of God’s cursing against impenitent sinners, gathered out of the seven and twentieth chapter of Deuteronomy, and other places of Scripture; and that ye should answer to every sentence, Amen: To the intent that, being admonished of the great indignation of God against sinners, ye may the rather be moved to earnest and true repentance; and may walk more warily in these dangerous days; fleeing from such vices, for which ye affirm with your own mouths the curse of God to be due.
</p>

<p>
CURSED is the man that maketh any carved or molten image, to worship it.
</p>

<p>
<i>And the people shall answer and say</i>,
</p>

<p>
<i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that curseth his father or mother.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that removeth his neighbour’s land-mark.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that maketh the blind to go out of his way.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that perverteth the judgement of the stranger, the fatherless, and widow.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that smiteth his neighbour secretly.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that lieth with his neighbour’s wife.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that taketh reward to slay the innocent.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed is he that putteth his trust in man, and taketh man for his defence, and in his heart goeth from the Lord.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Cursed are the unmerciful, fornicators, and adulterers, covetous persons, idolaters, slanderers, drunkards, and extortioners.
</p>

<p>
Answer: <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
<i>Minister</i>:
</p>

<p>
NOW seeing that all they are accursed (as the prophet David beareth witness) who do err and go astray from the commandments of God; let us (remembering the dreadful judgement hanging over our heads, and always ready to fall upon us) return unto our Lord God with all contrition and meekness of heart; bewailing and lamenting our sinful life, acknowledging and confessing our offences, and seeking to bring forth worthy fruits of penance. For now is the axe put unto the root of the trees, so that every tree that bringeth not forth good fruit is hewn down, and cast into the fire. It is a fearful thing to fall into the hands of the living God: He shall pour down rain upon the sinners, snares, fire and brimstone, storm and tempest; this shall be their portion to drink. For lo, the Lord is come out of his place to visit the wickedness of such as dwell upon the earth. But who may abide the day of his coming? Who shall be able to endure when he appeareth? His fan is in his hand, and he will purge his floor, and gather his wheat into the barn; but he will burn the chaff with unquenchable fire. The day of the Lord cometh as a thief in the night: and when men shall say, Peace, and all things are safe, then shall sudden destruction come upon them, as sorrow cometh upon a woman travailing with child, and they shall not escape. Then shall appear the wrath of God in the day of vengeance, which obstinate sinners, through the stubbornness of their heart, have heaped unto themselves; which despised the goodness, patience, and long-sufferance of God, when he calleth them continually to repentance. Then shall they call upon me (saith the Lord) but I will not hear; they shall seek me early, but they shall not find me; and that, because they hated knowledge, and received not the fear of the Lord, but abhorred my counsel, and despised my correction. Then shall it be too late to knock, when the door shall be shut; and too late to cry for mercy, when it is the time of justice. O terrible voice of most just judgement, which shall be pronounced upon them, when it shall be said unto them, Go, ye cursed, into the fire everlasting, which is prepared for the devil and his angels. Therefore, brethren, take we heed betime, while the day of salvation lasteth; for the night cometh, when none can work: But let us, while we have the light, believe in the light, and walk as children of the light; that we be not cast into utter darkness, where is weeping and gnashing of teeth. Let us not abuse the goodness of God, who calleth us mercifully to amendment, and of his endless pity promiseth us forgiveness of that which is past, if with a perfect and true heart we return unto him. For though our sins be as red as scarlet, they shall be made white as snow; and though they be like purple, yet they shall be made white as wool. Turn ye (saith the Lord) from all your wickedness, and your sin shall not be your destruction: Cast away from you all your ungodliness that ye have done: Make you new hearts, and a new spirit: Wherefore will ye die, O ye house of Israel? seeing that I have no pleasure in the death of him that dieth, saith the Lord God. Turn ye then, and ye shall live. Although we have sinned, yet have we an Advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous; and he is the propitiation for our sins. For he was wounded for our offences, and smitten for our wickedness. Let us therefore return unto him, who is the merciful receiver of all true penitent sinners; assuring ourselves that he is ready to receive us, and most willing to pardon us, if we come unto him with faithful repentance; if we submit ourselves unto him, and from henceforth walk in his ways; if we will take his easy yoke and light burden upon us, to follow him in lowliness, patience, and charity, and be ordered by the governance of his Holy Spirit; seeking always his glory, and serving him duly in our vocation with thanksgiving. This if we do, Christ will deliver us from the curse of the law, and from the extreme malediction which shall light upon them that shall be set on the left hand; and he will set us on his right hand, and give us the gracious benediction of his Father, commanding us to take possession of his glorious kingdom: Unto which he vouchsafe to bring us all, for his infinite mercy. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
<i>Then shall they all kneel upon their knees, and the Priest and Clerks kneeling (in the place where they are accustomed to say the Litany) shall say this Psalm</i>.
</p>

<p>
<i>Miserere mei, Deus</i>. Psalm 51
</p>

<p>
HAVE mercy upon me, O God, after thy great goodness : according to the multitude of thy mercies do away mine offences.
</p>

<p>
Wash me throughly from my wickedness : and cleanse me from my sin.
</p>

<p>
For I acknowledge my faults : and my sin is ever before me.
</p>

<p>
Against thee only have I sinned, and done this evil in thy sight : that thou mightest be justified in thy saying, and clear when thou art judged.
</p>

<p>
Behold, I was shapen in wickedness : and in sin hath my mother conceived me.
</p>

<p>
But lo, thou requirest truth in the inward parts: and shalt make me to understand wisdom secretly.
</p>

<p>
Thou shalt purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean : thou shalt wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow.
</p>

<p>
Thou shalt make me hear of joy and gladness: that the bones which thou hast broken may rejoice.
</p>

<p>
Turn thy face away from my sins : and put out all my misdeeds.
</p>

<p>
Make me a clean heart, O God : and renew a right spirit within me.
</p>

<p>
Cast me not away from thy presence : and take not thy holy Spirit from me.
</p>

<p>
O give me the comfort of thy help again : and stablish me with thy free Spirit.
</p>

<p>
Then shall I teach thy ways unto the wicked: and sinners shall be converted unto thee.
</p>

<p>
Deliver me from blood-guiltiness, O God, thou that art the God of my health : and my tongue shall sing of thy righteousness.
</p>

<p>
Thou shalt open my lips, O Lord : and my mouth shall shew thy praise.
</p>

<p>
For thou desirest no sacrifice, else would I give it thee : but thou delightest not in burnt-offering.
</p>

<p>
The sacrifice of God is a troubled spirit : a broken and contrite heart, O God, shalt thou not despise.
</p>

<p>
O be favourable and gracious unto Sion : build thou the walls of Jerusalem.
</p>

<p>
Then shalt thou be pleased with the sacrifice of righteousness, with the burnt-offerings and oblations : then shall they offer young bullocks upon thine altar.
</p>

<p>
Glory be to the Father, and to the Son : and to the Holy Ghost;
</p>

<p>
Answer: As it was in the beginning, is now, and ever shall be : world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Lord, have mercy upon us.
</p>

<p>
<i>Christ, have mercy upon us</i>.
</p>

<p>
Lord, have mercy upon us.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name, Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done, in earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread; And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us; And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
Minister: O Lord, save thy servants;
</p>

<p>
Answer: That put their trust in thee.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Send unto them help from above.
</p>

<p>
Answer: And evermore mightily defend them.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Help us, O God our Saviour.
</p>

<p>
Answer: And for the glory of thy Name deliver us; be merciful unto us sinners, for thy Name’s sake.
</p>

<p>
Minister: O Lord, hear our prayer.
</p>

<p>
Answer: And let our cry come unto thee.
</p>

<p>
Minister: Let us pray.
</p>

<p>
O LORD, we beseech thee, mercifully hear our prayers, and spare all those who confess their sins unto thee; that they, whose consciences by sin are accused, by thy merciful pardon may be absolved; through Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
O MOST mighty God, and merciful Father, who hast compassion upon all men, and hatest nothing that thou hast made; who wouldest not the death of a sinner, but that he should rather turn from his sin, and be saved: Mercifully forgive us our trespasses; receive and comfort us, who are grieved and wearied with the burden of our sins. Thy property is always to have mercy; to thee only it appertaineth to forgive sins. Spare us therefore, good Lord, spare thy people, whom thou hast redeemed; enter not into judgement with thy servants, who are vile earth, and miserable sinners; but so turn thine anger from us, who meekly acknowledge our vileness, and truly repent us of our faults, and so make haste to help us in this world, that we may ever live with thee in the world to come; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
<i>Then shall the people say this that followeth, after the Minister</i>.
</p>

<p>
TURN thou us, O good Lord, and so shall we be turned. Be favourable, O Lord, Be favourable to thy people, Who turn to thee in weeping, fasting, and praying. For thou art a merciful God, Full of compassion, long-suffering, and of great pity. Thou sparest when we deserve punishment, And in thy wrath thinkest upon mercy. Spare thy people, good Lord, Spare them, and let not thine heritage be brought to confusion. Hear us, O Lord, for thy mercy is great, And after the multitude of thy mercies look upon us; Through the merits and mediation of thy blessed Son, Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
<i>Then the Minister alone shall say</i>,
</p>

<p>
THE Lord bless us, and keep us; the Lord lift up the light of his countenance upon us, and give us peace, now and for evermore. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-22-ash-wednesday-commination.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-22-ash-wednesday-commination.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Ash Wednesday, or the First Day of Lent]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Ash Wednesday, or the First Day of Lent
</p>

<p>
ALMIGHTY and everlasting God, who hatest nothing that thou hast made, and dost forgive the sins of all those who are penitent; Create and make in us new and contrite hearts, that we, worthily lamenting our sins and acknowledging our wretchedness. may obtain of thee, the God of all mercy, perfect remission and forgiveness; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is Lent, the liturgical color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-22-ash-wednesday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-22-ash-wednesday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Shrove Tuesday]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Shrove Tuesday/Shrovetide
</p>

<p>
Shrove \Shrove\,
     imp. of {Shrive}.
     [1913 Webster]
</p>

<p>
{Shrove Sunday}, Quinguagesima Sunday.
</p>

<p>
{Shrove Tuesday}, the Tuesday following Quinguagesima Sunday,
   and preceding the first day of Lent, or Ash Wednesday.
</p>

<p>
Note: It was formerly customary in England, on this day, for
      the people to confess their sins to their parish
      priests, after which they dined on pancakes, or
      fritters, and the occasion became one of merriment. The
      bell rung on this day is popularly called Pancake Bell,
      and the day itself Pancake Tuesday. &#x2013;P. Cyc.
      [1913 Webster]
</p>

<p>
Shrive \Shrive\, v. t. [imp. {Shrived}or {Shrove}; p. p.
     {Shriven}or {Shrived}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Shriving}.] [OE.
     shriven, schriven, AS. scr[imac]van to shrive, to impose
     penance or punishment; akin to OFries. skr[imac]va to impose
     punishment; cf. OS. biskr[imac]ban to be troubled. Cf.
     {Shrift}, {Shrovetide}.]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li><p>
To hear or receive the confession of; to administer
confession and absolution to; &#x2013; said of a priest as the
agent.
</p>

<p>
That they should shrive their parishioners. &#x2013;Piers
				      Plowman.
</p>

<p>
Doubtless he shrives this woman, . . .
Else ne&rsquo;er could he so long protract his speech.
				      &#x2013;Shak.
</p>

<p>
Till my guilty soul be shriven.       &#x2013;Longfellow.
</p></li>

<li><p>
To confess, and receive absolution; &#x2013; used reflexively.
</p>

<p>
Get you to the church and shrive yourself. &#x2013;Beau. &amp; Fl.
</p></li>
</ol>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-lent.html">Lent</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-21-shrove-tuesday.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-21-shrove-tuesday.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Sunday Called Quinquagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Sunday Called Quinquagesima, or the Sunday Next before Lent
</p>

<p>
O Lord, who hast taught us that all our doings without charity are nothing worth; Send thy Holy Ghost, and pour into our hearts that most excellent gift of charity, the very bond of peace and of all virtues, without which whosoever liveth is counted dead before thee. Grant this for thine only Son Jesus Christ’s sake. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season is pre-Lent, the liturgical color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-19-the-sunday-called-quinquagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-19-the-sunday-called-quinquagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 11:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[About Old Laptops]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Last week my rss feed brought me a post by ‘Solene’%’ about <a href="https://dataswamp.org/~solene/2022-06-22-openbsd-selling-arguments.html">”How I would sell OpenBSD as a salesperson”</a>. I’m always interested in seeing what other geeks, particularly writers, use for hardware and software, and I’ve been more than mildly interested in moving out of Linux back into a “real” UNIX eventually, which these days means one of the BSDs (FreeBSD, OpenBSD or NetBSD). And so I have a “BSDs” folder in Instapaper and there found links to several pages on Derek Sivers’ site that mention OpenBSD (stay with me, there is a point to these wanderings). The one that caught my eye most was <a href="https://sive.rs/uses">What I Use</a>.
</p>

<p>
I relate to Sivers’ approach to tools a lot, since he seems to buy good stuff and then keep it forever, although he’s quite well off and guided by a philosophical preference for buying and owning as little as possible, while I just insist that I’m much poorer than I really am. Parsing his list of hardware, his workstation is a “Silent Desktop PC” is top quality from 2014 (mine is about the same age based on parts from a server that hosted my last project ten years ago). We’re sort of on a par there.
</p>

<p>
His next entry is his laptop, a Lenovo ThinkPad T440s dating from 2013. That caught my eye. I have a stack of old laptops: two from 2011, an 11” Apple MacBook Pro and a 14” HP Elitebook 8460p, and a 14” 2001 IBM ThinkPad R32. They all work, and they all have issues when it comes to acting like a laptop (that is, allowing me to use Emacs away from my desk). For one thing, they all have battery issues. The HP and the IBM batteries are completely dead, and the Mac’s is very weak. New batteries can be had easily enough, although in Apple style replacing the Mac battery would mean getting out my soldering gun.
</p>

<p>
I’ve never gotten completely comfortable with the Mac. It’s nice hardware—the case is wonderful and the keyboard is acceptable. It’s the software—and mainly MacOS—that I’ve never gotten completely accustomed to. It’s close enough to UNIX/Linux that I can do most of what I want to do, but then it throws a curve into the works that sends me to search for “the Mac way” to finish a job. And by now the trackpad is acting strange and I’m using a mouse when I need to use it (scanning and Kindle/Calibre are really the only things I use it for these days). I need to take some time off and see whether I can get the trackpad working right again.
</p>

<p>
The HP is OK. It’s pretty loud, a little heavy, the keyboard is kinda clunky. It’s running Ubuntu now, which worked for Valerie when it was her “desktop” but isn’t my cuppa tea. Perhaps with a working battery and a proper Debian installation it could be useful.
</p>

<p>
That twenty-year-old IBM ThinkPad really is my idea of a laptop I could live with, if it had a newer processor, batteries, wifi and was a little lighter. It might be just that I used ThinkPads during my stay at Northrop Grumman, but it has hands-down the best small keyboard, and the track-stick Just Works. That’s why Sivers’ ThinkPad T440s got my attention. It didn’t take long to learn that they are readily available on eBay an Amazon for $250 or less.
</p>

<p>
So, tempted as I am to just pick one and order it, I feel honor bound to see what I can do to get the MacBook and the HP running right and see whether I can “make do” first.
</p>

<p>
Stay tuned. I’ve been busy already.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-tech.html">tech</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[tech]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-13-about-old-laptops.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-13-about-old-laptops.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 11:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Sunday Called Sexagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Sunday Called Sexagesima, or the Second Sunday before Lent
</p>

<p>
O Lord God, who seest that we put not our trust in any thing that we do; Mercifully grant that by thy power we may be defended against all adversity; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
</p>

<p>
The Season is pre-Lent, the liturgical color is Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-12-the-sunday-called-sexagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-12-the-sunday-called-sexagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Nine]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for one Deceased — Day Nine
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
I GIVE YOU THANKS, O Lord, that you have created us to know and love you, and to live with each other in joyful companionship. In grief, strengthen my hope, and in sorrow, keep me from despair. Grant that Dean may go from strength to strength in the life of perfect service, and that I may so serve you here, that at the last, by your call, I will stand before you and with those whom I have loved but see no longer; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-11-day-nine.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-11-day-nine.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Eight]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for one Deceased — Day Eight
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
O LORD, OUR SAVIOR AND OUR JUDGE, by your passion and through your never failing mercies, grant forgiveness to Dean for all his sins, and rest from all the burdens he has carried; and by your Spirit, bring us all to acknowledge our sins that we may seek your forgiveness and make us patient and joyful to forgive one another for your sake; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-10-day-eight.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-10-day-eight.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 10:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Seven]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for one Deceased — Day Seven
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
GRANT, O LORD, that Dean, for whom I pray, may know the companionship of your blessed ones in heaven, and that we who mourn may be comforted and supported in the same blessed fellowship of love and prayer until we too come to our journey&rsquo;s end; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-09-day-seven.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-09-day-seven.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 11:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Six]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for one Deceased — Day Six
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
OF THE ABUNDANCE of your loving-kindness, O Lord, have mercy upon the soul of your servant Dean and, now that he is released from the weakness of mortality, restore him and give him a place in your everlasting salvation; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-08-day-six.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-08-day-six.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 08:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Five]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased — Day Five
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
GRANT US, WHO MOURN, grace that we may entrust Dean to your never-failing love; receive him into the arms of your mercy, and remember him according to the steadfast loving-kindness you show toward your people; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-07-day-five.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-07-day-five.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Four]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased — Day Four
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
HEAR THE PRAYER I bring before you, O Lord, that the soul of your servant Dean, which you have called to depart this life, may find a place in the eternal dwelling places of peace and light and be welcomed into the fellowship of your saints; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-06-day-four.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-06-day-four.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Sunday Called Septuagesima]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Sunday Called Septuagesima, or the Third Sunday before Lent
</p>

<p>
O Lord, we beseech thee favourably to hear the prayers of thy people; that we, who are justly punished for our offences, may be mercifully delivered by thy goodness, for the glory of thy Name; through Jesus Christ our Saviour, who liveth and reigneth with thee and the Holy Ghost ever, one God, world without end. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
The Season changes to pre-Lent, the liturgical color is now Purple.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-the-sunday-called-septuagesima.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-the-sunday-called-septuagesima.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Three]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased — Day Three
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
O GOD, YOUR MERCIES are more than we can know; hear my prayer for Dean and welcome him into the land of light and joy, in the fellowship of all your saints; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-day-three.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-05-day-three.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day Two]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased — Day Two
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
TO YOU, O LORD, I commend the soul of your servant Dean, that being dead to the world, he may live to you; and whatever sins he has committed, through the frailty of our mortal nature, graciously wash away by the pardon of your most merciful loving kindness; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-04-day-two.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-04-day-two.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 18:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Day One]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Nine Days of Prayer for One Deceased — Day One
</p>

<p>
For my late brother-in-law, Dr. Dean Presnall
</p>

<p>
V. Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I shall fear no evil.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Surely your goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
</p>

<p>
R. I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
</p>

<p>
V. Rest eternal grant to them, O Lord;
</p>

<p>
R. And let light perpetual shine upon them.
</p>

<p>
O GOD, YOU ARE FULL OF MERCY and ready to forgive; receive our prayers for the soul of your servant Dean, whom you have now called to depart out of this world: deliver him out of the hand of the enemy, hold him in everlasting remembrance, and command your holy angels to receive him and bring him into paradise: that as his hope and faith were in you, he may without fear or suffering enter the joys of eternal life; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
OUR Father, which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy Name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done, On earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread. And forgive us our trespasses, As we forgive them that trespass against us. And lead us not into temptation, But deliver us from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>

<p>
May the souls of the faithful departed, through the mercies of God, rest in peace. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-prayer.html">prayer</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-03-day-one.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-02-03-day-one.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 18:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Fourth Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Fourth Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
O God, who knowest us to be set in the midst of so many and great dangers, that by reason of the frailty of our nature we cannot always stand upright; Grant to us such strength and protection, as may support us in all dangers, and carry us through all temptations; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-29-the-fourth-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-29-the-fourth-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 10:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Third Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Third Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
Almighty and everlasting God, mercifully look upon our infirmities, and in all our dangers and necessities stretch forth thy right hand to help and defend us; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-22-the-third-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-22-the-third-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 10:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Second Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Second Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
Almighty and everlasting God, who dost govern all things in heaven and earth; Mercifully hear the supplications of thy people, and grant us thy peace all the days of our life; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-15-the-second-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-15-the-second-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The First Sunday after the Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The First Sunday after the Epiphany
</p>

<p>
O Lord, we beseech thee mercifully to receive the prayers of thy people who call upon thee; and grant that they may both perceive and know what things they ought to do, and also may have grace and power faithfully to fulfil the same; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-08-the-first-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-08-the-first-sunday-after-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Collect for The Epiphany]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
The Collect for The Epiphany, or the Manifestation of Christ to the Gentiles
</p>

<p>
O God, who by the leading of a star didst manifest thy only-begotten Son to the Gentiles; Mercifully grant that we, who know thee now by faith, may after this life have the fruition of thy glorious Godhead; through the same thy Son Jesus Christ our Lord. <i>Amen</i>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-liturgy.html">liturgy</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-06-the-collect-for-the-epiphany.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2023-01-06-the-collect-for-the-epiphany.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 10:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[I'm Back!]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Yes, I’m back - yes, I know it’s been close to a year. There is a reason—actually several reasons over and above my tendancy to put things off. There will be some explanation and some catch-up, but not today. Not that long ago I reinstalled my accustomed OS, rebuilt emacs and rewrote my init.el, and am today getting some gitting caught up. So, the test I’m referring to is whether org-static-blog is dtrt, whether I can push to gist. Typing is hard with fingers crossed, so that’s it for now.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-testing.html">testing</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[testing]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-12-12-i'm-back!.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-12-12-i'm-back!.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 14:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Does it Matter?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Having asked “What is Truth?” and explored the flip side, falsehood, an obvious follow-on question becomes “Does it Matter?” Whether it’s a matter of our own thoughts or what others present to us, does truth or falsehood matter?
</p>

<p>
Should I be concerned whether I’m being told the truth, or whether I’m being lied to? Whether my own thought processes are in line with “consensus reality” or I’m seriously deluded? Does truth matter?
</p>

<p>
Certainly, sometimes it does, but then again, sometimes it doesn’t.
</p>

<p>
If I ask “Is this mushroom safe to eat?” as I’m about to pop it into my mouth, and my friend says, “Sure, perfectly safe” whether that’s true or false could be a matter of life or death. On the other hand, if I say Liv Tyler played Galadriel in the Lord of the Rings movies, and my friend agrees, we’d both be wrong, but it’s not likely to matter much at all — unless I’m about to bet my life savings on the answer.
</p>

<p>
So, whether telling the truth is important is entirely context-dependent. It depends on the consequences. Or is it? Is there some value to truth, or loss to error, that’s more subtle than these examples would suggest?
</p>

<p>
That’s a good question and one that’s going to take some more examination. We’ll come back to that one.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-02-06-does-it-matter.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-02-06-does-it-matter.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 12:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[What is Falsehood?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“All generalizations are false, including this one.”—Mark Twain
</p>

<p>
If Truth is “in conformity to fact or reality”, there must be something <i>not</i> in conformity to fact or reality. And of course there is:
</p>

<p>
Falsehood \False&ldquo;hood\, n. [False + -hood]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li>Want of truth or accuracy; an untrue assertion or
representation; error; misrepresentation; falsity.</li>
<li>A deliberate intentional assertion of what is known to be
untrue; a departure from moral integrity; a lie.</li>
<li>Treachery; deceit; perfidy; unfaithfulness.</li>
<li>A counterfeit; a false appearance; an imposture.</li>
</ol>
<p>
Syn: Falsity; lie; untruth; fiction; fabrication.
</p>

<p>
And, like truth, there’s a lot of weeds to get into regarding falsehood. Oh, it doesn’t always have to be complicated. In software development, for instance, we use Boolean or bivalent logic to determine whether a value is, say, equal to or greater than 100. If it is, the answer is “true” (or 1 in computer speak) and if it isn’t, it’s “false” (or 0). Very straightforward and clean.
</p>

<p>
Once we introduce a human into the mix, though, it gets complicated very quickly. Ask a person an equally straightforward question — say, “Do you have twenty dollars with you?” and the reply is “No”. If the answer, whether it’s “yes” or “no” is true, accurate, “in conformity to fact or reality” we’ve arrived at end of story.
</p>

<p>
However, if the answer is not true, not “in conformity to fact or reality” things get a bit more complicated. If we got an inaccurate reply in the computer example, that’s an error and our code is faulty or there’s a hardware issue. However, if our friend did have twenty dollars and said “no”, or didn’t and said “yes”, then there are several possibilities.
</p>

<p>
A simple mistake is one — definition 1. above. She left home with $35 and bought a $15 book before we met up. That leaves $20 in her mind, but she forgot sales tax and that $20 is actually $18.45. Or, she may believe that we’ll think less of her if she’s not carrying at least $20 dollars, so she says that she does when she knows that she doesn’t. In other words, we’ve been lied to — definition 2.
</p>

<p>
More complicated than simple Boolean logic, but still fairly straightforward. Of course, because we’ve introduced humans into the picture, there are additional complications. For example, there’s the classic “Does this dress make my butt look big” or “Am I too old to be playing rock ‘n’ roll?” Of course, if you’re being asked either the answer may well be “Yes”, and a “No” answer would be a lie, but a complicated lie. The complication will have to do at least in part with motivation — a lie to avoid hurting someone’s feelings with no other consequences isn’t quite the same as an identical lie to harm the other person. Lies are complicated enough to deserve further exploration.
</p>

<p>
“Want of truth” and “an untrue assertion” in the definition eventually sends us back to the definition of “true”, which includes much more than “in conformity to fact or reality.” It also includes “conformity to rule”, “that which is true or certain concerning any matter or subject”, and “righteousness; true religion”.
</p>

<p>
These aspects of “truth” bring in context — truth in “conformity to rule” depends on which rule. Dribbling the ball is required in basketball, an error in American football.
</p>

<p>
“That which is true or certain concerning any matter or subject” depends on the subject. A true statement about gravity when the subject is Newtonian physics is false if the subject is switched to Einsteinian physics.
</p>

<p>
And, of course, “Righteousness; true religion” depends not only upon which religion, but which sect within a given religion.
</p>

<p>
So, it looks like, before we can get down and dirty with saying things that conform with reality, we may need to explore not-truth a bit more.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-30-what-is-falsehood.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-30-what-is-falsehood.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 13:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[What is Truth?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“What is Truth?”—Pontius Pilate, Roman Prefect/Procurator of Palestine, 26-36 Anno Domini, quoted in John 18:38.
</p>

<p>
Pilate gets a bad rap for asking, but in truth, “truth” is complicated. My primary dictionaries, the 1913 <i>Webster’s Revised Unabridged</i> of 1913 and the <i>Oxford Universal</i> of 1933 agree on four primary meanings (the following from the <i>Webster’s</i> with examples removed):
</p>

<p>
Truth \Truth\, n.; pl. {Truths}. [OE. treuthe, trouthe, treowpe,
     AS. tre[&rsquo;o]w?. See {True}; cf. {Troth}, {Betroth}.]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li>The quality or being true; as:
(a) Conformity to fact or reality; exact accordance with
    that which is, or has been; or shall be.
(b) Conformity to rule; exactness; close correspondence
    with an example, mood, object of imitation, or the
    like.
(c) Fidelity; constancy; steadfastness; faithfulness.
(d) The practice of speaking what is true; freedom from
    falsehood; veracity.</li>
<li>That which is true or certain concerning any matter or
subject, or generally on all subjects; real state of
things; fact; verity; reality.</li>
<li>A true thing; a verified fact; a true statement or
proposition; an established principle, fixed law, or the
like; as, the great truths of morals.</li>
<li>Righteousness; true religion.</li>
</ol>

<p>
Very interesting (or maybe not at all interesting), but just why is this Sunday the day to bring up dictionaries and definitions of grand, overarching theoretical notions like “truth”?
</p>

<p>
Fair question. My point – and I do have one — is that I fiddled about with the tech to get this little corner of the Internet (as we used to say in the early ‘90s) two weeks ago and have said “Hello”, described the tech that I fiddled about with and dropped a few pithy quotes. Now what? What are we doing here? Will it be more of the same — a bit of technology, some brief quotes with no commentary, just a little of this and some of that? Or is there going to be a theme?
</p>

<p>
A theme — that’s the ticket! Truth would make a dandy theme — telling the truth (as I see it) about technology, dropping quotes that seem to be truthful, yes. And probably deeper into the weeds. That definition suggests that there’s a lot of leeway in truth as a topic: what are the facts; what is reality — really — what is, or has been, or shall be; what actually is conformity to — whatever; what does fidelity, constancy, steadfastness and faithrulness demand; and what are we called upon to speak — how do we avoid falseness?
</p>

<p>
Is that too pompous? Looking at the <i>Websters</i> again, there’s certainly some risk of pomposity in the second definition — we’ll have to be careful:
</p>

<p>
Pompous \Pomp&ldquo;ous\, a. [F. pompeux, L. pomposus. See {Pomp}.]
</p>
<ol class="org-ol">
<li>Displaying pomp; stately; showy with grandeur;
magnificent; as, a pompous procession.</li>
<li>Ostentatious; pretentious; boastful; vainlorious; as,
pompous manners; a pompous style.</li>
</ol>

<p>
On the other hand, it’s certainly something to aspire to — bringing a little truth into the discussion. We’ll just have to wait and see.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-truth.html">truth</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-23-what-is-truth.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-23-what-is-truth.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 13:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[The Science is Certain]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“If you thought that science was certain — well, that is just an error on your part.”—Richard P. Feynman, <i>The Quotable Feynman</i>, p. 349, Princeton University Press
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-feynman.html">feynman</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[feynman]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-the-science-is-certain.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-the-science-is-certain.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 20:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[A Strange Superstition]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
“The strange superstition has arisen in the Western world that we can start all over again, remaking human nature, human society, and the possibilities of happiness, as though the knowledge and experience of our ancestors were now entirely irrelevant.”—Sir Roger Scruton, <i>Becoming a Family</i>, <a href="https://www.city-journal.org/html/becoming-family-11806.html">City Journal</a>, Spring, 2001
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-totd.html">totd</a> <a href="https://www.dasmith.xyz/tag-foreign.html">foreign</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[totd]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[foreign]]></category>
  <link>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-a-strange-superstition.html</link>
  <guid>https://www.dasmith.xyz/2022-01-16-a-strange-superstition.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 13:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
